<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Studio Zenkai on Studio Zenkai </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://studiozenkai.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:00:00 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foulab : Montreal’s creative space for hardware makers</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/foulab-hackerspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/foulab-hackerspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Foulab is a space for hardware makers, with the idea that any smart individual can imagine and create new innovative electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few metro stations away from downtown Montreal, Foulab is located in an industrial building, the kind you would expect to see hosting a rave party.
Before coming to Foulab, you’ll see a studio for artists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2854/12206121575_3d02a513c8_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FOULAB IS AT THE INTERSECTION OF GEEKINESS, ART, HACKING, AND MAKER MOVEMENT.&#34; title=&#34;FOULAB IS AT THE INTERSECTION OF GEEKINESS, ART, HACKING, AND MAKER MOVEMENT.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiercely independent, Foulab is not sponsored by any government or corporation. It’s run by its members, in a way similar to coops. Members join in to work on various maker projects, learn electronics or meet other like-minded montrealers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5515/12206354633_bb03879fae_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;
The space is currently maintained by 12 members but they hope to get to 16 members soon. With various workspaces as well as a lounge area, Foulab welcomes many visitors and friends on its open doors tuesday nights. It also hosts frequently public events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2838/12206745736_4cacb36304_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s Foulab’s logo, an electronics version. You’ll see it proudly shown everywhere in the space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5501/12206527484_b7f25cae0d_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foulab has been 100% financially independent for the past 4 years, with hardware hackathons, workshops, and through members contributions. In the long term, they hope to get more machines (such as large 3D printers), similar to what’s seen in other Canadian cities. Alex helps manage the space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5521/12206529644_d51530f019_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronics new and old are stocked, donated by members and friends of Foulab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7343/12206528994_de5458fbd8_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are servers, other exotic computers, and even mechanical teletypewriters! Here’s a 30-year-ish old Apple II computer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2835/12207203654_db187a67eb_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting in a space like Foulab is the ability to use advanced tools like oscilloscopes or other tools that could be too expensive for an individual to own or rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue is also noise and other nuisance that will make your neighbor ask questions what you are doing. Better come to a space where you are free and encourage to work on your project. Here’s a member who’s working on a geo-locating mechanism for his rocketry hobby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7387/12206529924_476597ef08_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a soldering station for electronics work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7332/12206528184_2fd7376a39_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foulab has of course dozens of different electronic parts, to repair electronics, build new ones, or just have fun:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3805/12206743386_3969967070_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;
They also have heavy-duty tools and machinery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7394/12206531064_46492ef244_b.jpg&#34;&gt;THERE’S ALWAYS SOMETHING INSPIRING BY BEING IN A SPACE WHERE YOU COULD CREATE ANY KIND OF MACHINE AND ELECTRONICS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are various 3D printers at Foulab, small and large scale. Here’s one that’s being built :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7420/12206527134_2f92f80f9b_b.jpg&#34;&gt;THERE’S ALWAYS SOMETHING INSPIRING BY BEING IN A SPACE WHERE YOU COULD CREATE ANY KIND OF MACHINE AND ELECTRONICS.&lt;/a&gt;
Here’s a musical instrument done at a public maker event. There are wooden keys as well as a paper score where the air would go through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7404/12206529114_5af14e2ca1_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an amplifier creatively made with off-the-shelf transistor costing about $3, whereas brands typically use transistors costing 20 times more. Good ingenuity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3672/12206743006_bec6d9f0e6_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Foulab members like also to work on fun projects, such as this LED display:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5473/12206529354_df17038033_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;
The crowd at Foulab is a mix of programmers, techies, travelers, artists and generally free-thinkers and innovators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3740/12206355073_77eaec8202_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the open doors tuesdays nights, you can talk to members and visitors, or head to one of the workspace and do a soldering job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3821/12206358403_f3ae26b2fb_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members travel also to various science and maker conferences, and are in a way, part of a global network:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7419/12207946586_df06aee648_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foulab is also a coworking space – at $75/month, you’ve got a space to work on your project. Here, we’ve got 2 people working on a sysadmin tool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3774/12206356743_a27710eeb2_b.jpg&#34;&gt;photo foulab montreal hackerspace&lt;/a&gt;
Get more information on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://foulab.org/&#34;&gt;Foulab website&lt;/a&gt; – I recommend going to the space around 8 or 9pm on Tuesdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos by @heri with Canon EOS-M + 22m pancake&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Science Is Not Necessarily Good For You</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/thoughts-on-latest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:35:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/thoughts-on-latest-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/truckers.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;truckers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A convoy of truckers gathered in Canada&amp;rsquo;s federal capital last week. They protested vaccine mandates but rode on a wave of discontentment against lockdown, inflation and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many right-leaning Canadians value their &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; to do what they want, above general public health. They state that they will build immunity naturally and let covid19 run its course. This is on top of a belief that distrust anything from government &amp;amp; institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side, locals in Ottawa or Toronto label them as selfish, anti-science rednecks. Let&amp;rsquo;s get vaccinated, two, three or more times, they say, and be done with the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not comment on social issues, but my personal opinion is that latest science is not necessarily good for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, studies have proven that the messenger RNA vaccines significantly improve immunity against Covid, prevent severe hospitalization and lower mortality rate. This is a major breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But history demonstrates major technology breakthroughs has pitfalls years or decades later:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclear energy creates absurd amounts of energy but brings cancer,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plastic is an amazing material but also brings cancer and pollution. I can name many other &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; materials such as asbestos that wreaks havoc wherever you use them,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ICE engines revolutionized transport but brought in part &lt;a href=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/post/climate-change-you-me/&#34;&gt;climate change&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social media is amazing for entertainment but creates mental health issues in kids &amp;amp; teenagers,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food processing technologies are amazing and brings us delicious french fries, ice cream &amp;amp; soda. But they also increase risks of obesity &amp;amp; diabetes Type 2,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are countless examples but the general gist is that technology or the latest science will bring serious issues, often many decades later, especially when said technology is too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, messenger RNA vaccines are amazing and almost a miracle. But so far, there has been no studies on the long term consequences. Are there any side effects on immunity or precursor cells, twenty years down the line? Who knows. Myself, I have been double vaccinated. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong in using the latest science at a critical moment, such as a life threatening situation. But I do not think we should trust blindly the latest science. Take a step back, review what is available with a grain of salt, and think about the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Playbook</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the idea of playbook, which is basically a recipe to win a case. It can be in a team sports situation, such as how to score in American football in a given situation. It can be used by a salesperson, such as how to win a commercial contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagined what would be my Ruby Engineering playbook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on hard projects that move the needle in the long-term, or alternatively easy wins (less than a day to implement+deploy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not reinvent the wheel. Research different approaches before trying to come up with your design. Reuse when possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When faced with a big block, divide, then conquer or delegate or delay. Divide means tackling the blocker in manageable chunks. The second means that I should either solve it myself, have another service solve it, or delay processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When implementing, remove as much as possible. Introduce only what&amp;rsquo;s needed to make it work, as if keystrokes were a limited resource, and copy/paste did not exist. Succinctness is underrated !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faced with loops, arrays or iterations, have a log(n) or faster implementation, as if you had a CPU from last century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be able to explain your design or algorithm orally to another person, without them able to see any code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not create side-effects in other people&amp;rsquo;s work. Assume future maintainers won&amp;rsquo;t be smart so make your implementation idiot-proof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before committing, ask if it is the best you can commit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase test cooverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always run linting / test suite before commit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note : this is a WIP&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop command line alternative</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/docker-desktop-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 18:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/docker-desktop-replacement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker Desktop is one of the de facto tool present on macos developer machines, along with other utilities such as git or homebrew. Contrary to apps such as VS Code, it not an app you interact with everyday but more a background tool running constantly during application development and deployment. It runs in fact the virtual machine that allows you to run docker on Windows or Mac as if you were on Linux, albeit with a little bit more resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many users will need to look for alternatives with the recent announcement that it will now be a paid subscription for medium to large companies. On MacOS, I use docker-machine to run docker from Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;brew install &amp;ndash;cask docker virtualbox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might need to authorize this in MacOS preferences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;brew install docker-machine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I setup docker-machine with more memory &amp;amp; CPU, since I work on large Ruby and Python/tensorflow projects. Codebases with a small footprint can use the default virtualbox settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker-machine create -d virtualbox &amp;ndash;virtualbox-memory=4096 &amp;ndash;virtualbox-cpu-count=2 &amp;ndash;virtualbox-disk-size=10000 default&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See if it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker run hello-world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you should be able to run docker, docker-compose, build, tag and run images!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note 1 : Compared to Docker Desktop, you have to manually setup port forwarding once you build and run an image, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vboxmanage controlvm default natpf1 &amp;ldquo;nameformapping,tcp,,3000,,3000&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes puma available on localhost:3000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note 2 : If you reboot your machine or if it goes into sleep, docker-machine can stop. Run it again with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker-machine start default&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know how it works for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/remote-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Canada, as well as many countries, Covid-19 infections is exponentially decreasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are on the verge of getting our old life back, from going to restaurants or to the cinemas, and why not have a celebratory drink with friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before moving on, I would like to share how I remote work, one of the main traits of the Covid-19 pandemic. I hope this helps other remote workers, and encourage developers and companies to adopt it on a permanent basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not by all means the most productive person. To the contrary. In February 2021, when it got grim, I spent much of my time watching Netflix and eating snacks, and got nothing done. That was not pretty. However during the pandemic, I also learnt Python and setup data pipelines that serves AI models in 21 countries. I learnt Kubernetes and how to scale it on GCP. I designed &amp;amp; developed a complete CI/CD system with automated E2E tests and healthchecks. I consulted as a Ruby Senior engineer with various companies. In parallel, I closed a real estate deal as a short term rental business, and learnt how to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.ca/rooms/38450385?preview_for_ml=true&#34;&gt;deliver a 5 star customer service&lt;/a&gt;. All this within a busy personal &amp;amp; family life where nothing was sacrificed. So I consider myself organized &amp;amp; productive as a remote worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main dangers of remote working is being in an environment made for relaxing and enjoying hobbies. You might have a living room designed to enjoy the latest digital entertainment. Your kitchen can have the latest tasty treats 🤤. Nice books and toys are around, waiting for you. You could have kids, family or roommates asking for your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another danger is the lack of coworkers or direct superiors around. Certain people thrive on live social inputs, either negative or positive. They focus on work when they have someone around discussing work. Or they get motivation when the big boss is around. If nobody is around to care, how do you make things go forward?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One less visible danger is sedentarity. Going to a physical office forces you to one way or another to move. Office lunch will have you moving around, as well as meetings &amp;amp; breaks. If the office is downtown or a commercial zone, it is easy to go around shopping or go to the pub. Not anymore when the office is a desk at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outcomereference.com/causes/102&#34;&gt;Sedentarity leads to&lt;/a&gt; worse physical well-being, weight gain, as well as other ailments such as pre-diabetes. Add this to the lack of social environment and you have depression lurking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you work around these dangers? How do you stay productive? I share my &amp;ldquo;recipe&amp;rdquo; below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it is important to know what you want. It can be a job promotion. It can be to gather enough savings to afford a car or a house. It can be financial independence. Or it can be just as simple as learning a skill. In any case, fulfilling tasks or checking boxes assigned by another person is not enough. Having a goal will make sense of things and will keep you going when things go dark. So take some time to find this inner long-term motivation. It is OK to work on daily tasks set by others or by you, but make sure you also have in mind the &amp;ldquo;end goal&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it is also key to have a rhythm that works for you. Every day, I prepare and dress as if I would go to the office (yes, no sweat pants). Every morning, I walk a kilometer and get my dose of sunshine. If the desk is dirty, I will clean up before working. Then I sit down and list 5 to 10 tasks I should do today. I use MacOs&amp;rsquo;s free Notes software and I put first tasks that are dead easy so I can get the ball rolling. I can finish with one or two tasks on self-improvement, from reading technical articles to reviewing or learning something. Then it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of adding a bold &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; in front of every task as the day passes by. Usually I have a couple of tasks I can&amp;rsquo;t finish. I don&amp;rsquo;t make a big deal though. I&amp;rsquo;ll do them the next day, or I will break them into simpler tasks. Finally, at the end of the day, I&amp;rsquo;ll go out, walk or bike to the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s important here is making a difference between work and life. I work from 8:30am till 5:30pm. I don&amp;rsquo;t think about leisure during those times. Nor do I work on evenings. Of course, there are exceptions but the most important is to have a single-minded focus when you do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the lack of social connections, I find having a hobby or your own &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; avoids having negative thoughts fill your mind. This year, I had to take care of a &amp;ldquo;chalet&amp;rdquo; and also make it &lt;a href=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/post/airbnb-vacation-home/&#34;&gt;available as a vacation home rental&lt;/a&gt;. I started screwing doors, glue cabinets, repair furniture, paint decks, learn about spa chemistry and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s a thousand little things that I knew nothing about and it is more than enough to get my mind busy during the pandemic. I know others who got into woodworking, writing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/post/autonomous-rc-car/&#34;&gt;building an autonomous RC car&lt;/a&gt;. Pick what you like and run with it, otherwise you will get lost soon on Netflix, or start wondering about the meaning of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, more than ever, I was connected to the family, high school groups, and dear friends. It seems as though the lack of physical social connections made me more connected online, more than ever. WhatsApp groups &amp;amp; Facebook made it possible through daily messages and regular video calls. Why is this important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a city or a university campus, being around a tight knit group will give you frequent social cues on what the group considers &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;. For example, this is how you decide to work on a job promotion because you&amp;rsquo;ll make everyone around you jealous or try to get a convertible roadster. Good or not, these social cues makes us move mountains. Having a strong network online, on Facebook groups or on WhatApp is similar to this idea, so you can get frequent social cues to move your b*tt and get things going&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the actual desk setup?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many mention having dual screens, and a wide array of hardware and software for efficient remote work. I find if I have an uncluttered desk, a &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; seat, acceptable noise level, and acceptable Internet then I am good to go. It is easy to get lost in having the latest gadget or the latest noise cancelling headphones. One important thing though : your setup might not be important but interruptions are. So if you have noisy kids or roommates, find a way to manage those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy remote working! If you find this article interesting, add a comment below or hit me up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/heri&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I am cancelling Amazon Prime</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/cancel-amazon-prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 06:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/cancel-amazon-prime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided this morning to cancel my Amazon Prime membership. I used it for free prime delivery, and also for occasional prime videos, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Elementary-Season-1/dp/B009IJJ5B4&#34;&gt;excellent Elementary&lt;/a&gt; series. It is also amazing to say &amp;ldquo;Alexa, play french songs&amp;rdquo; and discover pieces from Amazon Music you knew nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a fan of the Amazon store. You could find rare items that were not sold anywhere else, at unbeatable prices. Reviews were genuine, and when an item had an average of 5-star, it only meant that it was an excellent product. I got items that allowed me to be more productive and more efficient, at lower prices. Physical stores such as Best Buy were only useful to help in the decision process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Amazon is unfortunately full of junk. The majority are cloned products of shoddy craftsmanship with little regard for durability, and boosted by 5 star reviews from users who got the product for free. Amazon Basics provide a standard of some sort but the line is comparable to IKEA products : they do the job but they are only meant to last for a year. When you do find interesting items, prices can be a multiple of what you find locally. Currently the only benefit is convenience : one click purchase with someone delivering boxes at your door step in a day or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand this kind of convenience is interesting for special cases. If you are a single parent or if you have special needs, nothing beats shopping from your bed and having someone package and deliver for you. You save time to focus on kids, and don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with stairs, traffic or possibly rude service. You might even be claustrophobic or mall-phobic. In my case though, it falls in the definition of luxury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue is the environmental footprint. I wrote recently about &lt;a href=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/post/climate-change-you-me/&#34;&gt;the climate emergency&lt;/a&gt;. You cannot be environmentally conscious and at the same time, make someone drive a van and waste boxes and plastic just for one gadget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/doorstep.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stacks of wasteful amazon boxes&#34; title=&#34;[stacks of wasteful amazon boxes]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently my biggest use for Amazon is for home renovation, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/post/airbnb-vacation-home/&#34;&gt;detailed in the Airbnb vacation home post&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever there was a problem, a quick search would find a solution on Amazon and get it delivered right away. I&amp;rsquo;ve now moved from Amazon to local retailers such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.canac.ca&#34;&gt;canac&lt;/a&gt;. It is local home renovation chain, but without the costs of Home Depot. Issues are compiled, filtered. If issues are still listed after a week, I do one single canac run. Total costs are 2 to 3 times less than Amazon, and I also get to test and touch products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second use for Amazon is for electronics, since I work in tech and also have projects such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/post/autonomous-rc-car/&#34;&gt;autonomous robot cars&lt;/a&gt;. Like canac, you can always find local retailers that offer comparable products at lower prices. I get items in &amp;ldquo;bulk&amp;rdquo; so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go buy it again later. I also get boards and chips that are general purpose, so they can be reused for multiple projects. For speciality items like Lidar or AI chips, if I cannot find a second hand one, I will of course have to order from the manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gadgets are a special case. This is for example the phone holder for your car or bike that is waterproof and also does wireless charging or whatnot. Or it can be a USBa to USB-C cable that does X and Y at the same time. Or another kitchen tool that looks amazing &amp;hellip; at least on paper. I would encourage you to check if you cannot find it locally, better yet make it yourself. Or what about not having it all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had other use for Amazon Prime, such as clothing and others. For example, in November, I realize I am missing winter gear, so I would conveniently order a hat &amp;amp; a couple of gloves on Amazon. I am now looking into &amp;ldquo;buying for life&amp;rdquo; items. Patagonia or Arc&amp;rsquo;teryx provide durable products, with a lifetime guarantee. You can find similar brands for the kitchen, footwear and so on. Having lifetime products is certainly less sexy than having fashionable items every season, but I am afraid it is the way to lower our environmental footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I will miss Prime Videos for the occasional quirky or highbrow video. There is more than enough though on Netflix and I hope it will leave me more time for more productive endeavours, or why not, just enjoy outdoors 😁&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Climate Change means for you and me</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/climate-change-you-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 09:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/climate-change-you-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is Earth day and an excellent opportunity to reflect on human&amp;rsquo;s environmental impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic hit countries like a truck and changed overnight our ways of working or interacting with others. Many lost their jobs, others went into depression or worse got infected with COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of the disease was little discussed. It is clear for me though that human&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inverse.com/science/deforestation-disease-outbreak-study&#34;&gt;cancerous growth, especially deforestation&lt;/a&gt;, is linked to the pandemic. As humans develop further and encroach into nature, it gets into contact with new pathogens. Wildlife is disturbed, cycles are broken and as a result, diseases find new ways to propagate. Thus COVID-19 is directly linked to climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/deforestation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;deforestation photo&#34; title=&#34;[deforestation photo&#34; /&gt;
Deforestation Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@daveherring?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Dave Herring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous pandemics in South East Asia and others like Ebola in Africa tells us this is not a unique occurence. It is plausible another pandemic with high transmission rate will hit us in the short term. It is also plausible we will not be able to discover an efficient vaccine. What then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is not just mild heat discomfort in the summer. There were many factors at play, but one of the main origins of the civil war in Syria was drought. Farmers running out of water for their crops had no choice but emigrate to the cities, fuelling discontent and riots until civil war erupted. I can see the same scenario occur in Iraq, Sudan, Yemen, Tchad, and many other countries. Civilans will flee and then will find refugee in western countries, straining the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water scarcity is not just for &amp;ldquo;poor countries&amp;rdquo;. It is a regular occurence in California, Mediterranean countries, Australia, South Africa. In fact, a world map shows us its predominance worldwide. Populations will be forced to move elsewhere, and claim water, land, energy and more wherever they settle. How many more millions climate change refugees can you and me support?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/water-scarcity.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;water scarcity map&#34; title=&#34;[water scarcity map]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is obvious the climate emergency is going to practically change our short and long term future. The pandemic substantially increased the costs of basic goods such as food and housing. I expect price of land, water and energy to further increase in the next decade. Perhaps new security services will be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a private citizen, what can one do? If you haven&amp;rsquo;t done yet, take steps to secure your future. Don&amp;rsquo;t live in a water scarce zone or be in a country negatively impacted by climate change. You cannot also secure a future if your job and skills belong to an &amp;ldquo;oils &amp;amp; plastics&amp;rdquo; age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is also honourable and good is take personal steps to fight climate change. It can mean reducing your environmental footprint, by reducing consumption and why not, developing nature. Grow trees, plants and veggies, produce your own energy, stop buying &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo;, recycle &amp;amp; reuse, minimize car trips &amp;amp; flights etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/greenhouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;greenhouse photo&#34; title=&#34;[greenhouse photo]&#34; /&gt;
Greenhouse Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@zanda_photography?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Zanda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/wind-energy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wind energy photo&#34; title=&#34;[wind energy photo]&#34; /&gt;
Wind Farms Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@karsten_wuerth?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Karsten Würth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, your environmental footprint is proportional to your energy and financial expenses. Reducing your monthly expenses to nearly zero means that you managed to subtract yourself from the destructive system, and as a bonus, means also financial freedom 😁&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means supporting others who fight climate change: kids, neighbors, communities, companies and politicians. It takes a whole lot to repair what we broke. There is of course the alternative to quit and go find a future on Mars, but I do not quit, I am not
a billionaire, and it is not on my timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting a web application</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/stack-performance-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/stack-performance-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you diagnose a slow web application? What about an unresponsive web application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are questions I asked when interviewing recently developers. The questions are simple to understand yet complex to answer. Many applicants study data structures or various algorithms. Few  have a holistic view of web applications, due to lack of experience or because of niche specializations. They often work on a specific part of a web project, and have little appreciation of work done in back-end, front-end, devops or other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few answers I expected in case of a slow application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring tools is the first step. If there is no monitoring, then install or integrate one of the commercially available tools. Otherwise, it is like a doctor guessing what a patient has without doing any history, physical examination let alone blood work. Monitoring should output detailed information on past queries as well as exactly application stack trace. Be aware that certain monitoring tools do not log killed queries, such as gunicorn killing a worker if there is no response after 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A monitoring tool can show you what requests were slow. Malicious scripts can probe your app at specific times. It is also possible an external cron job does millions of queries, thereby impacting the whole userbase. Smart rules deal with this. What we care about are requests coming from genuine, paying users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After monitoring, you should have a series of test cases probing distinct parts of your stack. These scripts benchmark the database server, various parts of your application (authentication, pre-processing, ORM, data transformation, rendering etc.), as well as benchmarking caches and other layers. Ideally, the tests bring randomness in test cases &amp;amp; also depth and widness. This assume you have been many months on the job or your team had good engineering practises. If no such benchmarking &amp;amp; testing tools are not available, it is still possible to diagnose separately. In most cases, I would start with the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A database can be slow because of low memory. Increasing available RAM allows you to increase max connexions and will also decrease response times. It is also possible the database is on a different network or a different geo region. Lookup into getting the database as close as possible to the applications. The biggest issues in database usage is however the lack of database optimization. Is there proper indexing? Is there redundant data ? Do you have to do a &amp;ldquo;SELECT *&amp;rdquo; when often a couple of columns are enough to complete the query? Why are there dozens of requests on the users table when a single query is enough? Here, the KISS (Keep It Simple Stupid) principle should be followed as often as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s not because you can do multiple requests and get millions of rows that you should. I often set myself a budget of 3 to 4 max queries per endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algorithms and data algorithms can be slow. With modern programming languages such as Python or Ruby, it is a no brainer to add a loop. The developer will test the feature for 10 data points until a user wants a million data points. Now your loop is computed a million times. Like the database budget of 3 queries above, I set myself a maximum of 7 lines for each endpoint. It is extremely hard to output bloated data structures with such a small budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same simplicity idea, I have seen developers add layers upon layers of microservices for an endpoint. A user calls Flask, which calls a dictionary, which calls a tensorflow model on a VPN, and then more data transformations and more database calls are made . I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen S3 calls to dataframe done real-time for a publicly available endpoint. Please make it simple, ideally within the application &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; database pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is also possible to use the incorrect libraries. I have done business intelligence queries in Ruby while the same calculation would be 10 times faster in Python&amp;rsquo;s libraries (pandas &amp;amp; others). Even within the same programming language, you can pick a buggy, slow and outdated library. Yes it works and you got your pull request approved but the whole team now has to diagnose slow requests for the next 3 months :( Make sure to build on solid foundations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application server is the last I am going to diagnose. Having more memory &amp;amp; more processes work. Having the latest Ruby version or Rust version with the performance improvements helps. Remember though they are not going to save you when there is all the bloat above. Perhaps adding a load balancer with a bit replication helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all this is done and not much else can be optimized, it is possible to look at hacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An asynchronous job queue is a nice hack. You can acknowledge a user request as quickly as possible, and process the request when you can, taking as much time as you need. It is possible to use a UI element to notify user that the job is being processed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a redis cache is such a hack. You can have sub-100ms response time with a redis cache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a CDN can work too. Fastly does that, and it even takes keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about an application that is unresponsive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First an application can still be available but be so slow that users assume it&amp;rsquo;s dead. I lookup monitoring tools and other steps above to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what an application hits, in order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;domain name servers are queried. It is possible your name servers are dead or your domain name expired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the host might have issues. Look up their alert page and your account. Even mastodonts like AWS or GCP has issues from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your load-balancer or web server (nginx or other) is misconfigured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your application server (Rails, Flask, Django) did not start. Does it work locally? Does it have the correct env variables or args? Like the above, you can revert to the native configuration to make sure it works, before optimizing it later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the application server cannot connect to a critical service such as the database. Check up the host, the port, and credentails. Try to connect to bash to the server and then connect to the db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the application server cannot connect to caching services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you make the application load a lot of data during its startup phase. The application doesn&amp;rsquo;t find all the files (there&amp;rsquo;s always one missing..), or you forget to add a package to read a specialy binary format and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the database is empty or was emptied by a team member but needs startup data to actually works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are not enough resources (hard drive space, RAM, etc.). This happens for large applications with user-generated data or/and a sysadmin who didn&amp;rsquo;t setup correct monitoring tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, it is easy to write a bash script to automate checks for all the steps above and pintpoint issues. Additionally, most projects have a sysadmins who will take responsability for this. However, knowing how a web application works won&amp;rsquo;t hurt you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope all the above makes sense and helps you next time you have these issues or get the question. Until then, happy programming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting an Airbnb vacation home</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/airbnb-vacation-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/airbnb-vacation-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One year ago, I decided to purchase a waterfront cottage. It would be in the Laurentians aka Quebec&amp;rsquo;s cottage country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December and early January 2020, Twitter alerted me to the sanitary situation in China. It was clear it was coming this way. Since authorities didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to care, I thought it would be a complete disaster in North America, with the economy and infrastructure paralyzed. I also knew the stock market has been bullish for the past decade and bet it would crash. So let&amp;rsquo;s flee the incoming apocalypse, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cabin (aka &amp;ldquo;chalet&amp;rdquo;) hours away from any major city would be a safe haven against panic. It would be also a great way to park liquid assets against any hyperinflation or stock market crash. I also thought that if there was no pandemic, I could turn it into an vacation home that could be offered for weeks or weekends on platforms such as airbnb of vrbo. It is also a personal dream to have a waterfront chalet and be able to share it with friends &amp;amp; family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not an easy decision. It is easier to follow your 9 to 5 job or organize the vacation in the Dominican Republic. And to prepare the future, financial managers would tell you to put money in RRSPs and in life insurance. In contrast, putting this into place required:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doing market research and confirm that vacation homes could indeed be profitable, and are also legal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doing real estate research, and be willing to visit properties during the pandemic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn as much as possible about real estate, so as not to be conned by sharks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and be ready to seize the moment, even if risky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember having to visit a property when it was forbidden to travel between regions. Highway 15 is always busy and it was surreal to see it completely empty, except for one or two cars from cleaning companies. There were police barrages in Mont-Tremblant to dissuade Montrealers from coming in regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amidst ever increasing infections, government restrictions that I visited a log cabin, 1h45 from Montreal, in Rivière-Rouge. The cabin borders the river with heaps of white sand all around. It has 3 bedrooms, including one in the basement. I remember being blown away by the interior, the high ceiling, the warm colors. The architecture and the land were not too bad either. You could see yourself living here and be happy. One would happily fish in the morning and then take a couple of hours to take care of a greenhouse and a couple of honey bee hives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/cabin-summer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SummerCabin&#34; title=&#34;[summer cabin]&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/cabin-interior.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Interior&#34; title=&#34;[interior cabin]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.ca/rooms/38450385?preview_for_ml=true&#34;&gt;View the chalet on Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To top it, the previous owner already put it on Airbnb and would transfer keys and codes to me. It was also already decorated and furnished, ready for me or for any guests. This was a compelling argument. I had a couple of other properties in mind, with better location, or bigger/better. These however had to be furnished entirely and nobody wants to do that in the middle of a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the vacation home makes on an average about $5250 per month, except last October when the government issued stay-at-home orders. The majority of guests right now are small families looking to spend a weekend or a week, apart from the hustle &amp;amp; bustle of Montreal. There are also couples, or the occasional group of roommates who&amp;rsquo;ve had enough of seeing the same 4 walls. I send them a custom door code and a few basic instructions 72 hours before. Check-ins are automated. Families are self-sufficient, have the most fun of their lives for a few days. By the time they pack up, a highly professional cleaning crew comes and gets the property ready for the next family. The system works well, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbnb.ca/rooms/38450385?preview_for_ml=true&#34;&gt;the overwhelming positive reviews reflect this&lt;/a&gt;. Or you can try yourself and book a week, I can guarantee you will not be disappointed. Right now, it is still not profitable (at all) since I had to install a hot tub ($12k), install a 3-stage water filtration system, buy a washer/dryer combo, replace the stove, add a Sonos speaker, add Ring video cameras, amenities for kids and children and so on and so on, but it is in a good path of making $75k gross and $50k profit pretax 2 years from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in having your own Airbnb/vrbo vacation home, please however know it is not straightforward. I know a few who stopped because they couldn&amp;rsquo;t deal taking care of customers, and they couldn&amp;rsquo;t break even. There are others on the other hand who bring in $120k annually. The vast majority make just enough to pay costs and mortgage. To succeed, what&amp;rsquo;s essential is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;know what sells and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Location is key (Mont-Tremblant commands big $$$ while your shack in Gaspésie won&amp;rsquo;t). Lakefront is great, an alternative would be a ski-in/ski-out property near a popular ski station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it needs time, care and effort. It&amp;rsquo;s not passive revenue, to the contrary. Think yourself as a vacation resort operator whose primary goal is to deliver an amazing vacation experience to families. This is the attitude you have to adopt when communicating with customers or when giving directions to cleaning crews. If you have a full-time job, like I do, then you have to be tightly organized to make both work. Hopefully, I have never met vacation rental problems that were difficult to solve. Most are just solved by investing more time &amp;amp; care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carefully add amenities that increases average nightly rate. A hot tub increases rates by $100/night. Here are others that increase the nightly rate: a terrace with outdoor dining options, an amazing view, access to a beach, outdoor shower, a dock with boating, indoor options when weather is bad. Others offer unique activities such as gourmet tasting or kayaking sessions. Why not explore that avenue? Sky is the limit!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you need to monitor and control expenses. I know I wanted the best at the beginning. It is easy to spend endlessly for marginal benefits. Right now, I invest in 100% what&amp;rsquo;s necessary to maintain the property &amp;amp; the level of service and 70% of what&amp;rsquo;s required to deliver an amazing vacation experience. And I learnt to pass on 30% of the remaining. Otherwise, it is a bottomless money pit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a system that controls excess and risks. There are guests who want to party. Others do not clean-up. Others will break up stuff and hide it. This means you need to be creative on how to make them clean up or not want to have a party. Also this also means having a system that decreases reliance on other parties. It is not good to be 100% reliant on Airbnb or a maintenance crew. Airbnb can abuse its dominant power and your cleaning crew can one day ask for extravagant fees, or just tap out. What are you going to do then? Do you have an alternative?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I recommend having a partner. It can be a spouse, or a business partner. In my case, it was my brother &amp;amp; I. A partner allows you to bounce ideas, to get priorities sorted, and prevent splurging on expensive amenities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this project was a great learning experience on how to operate a business and provide good to great customer service. It was not easy for me. In software engineering, you can strive for perfection. Here, you have to be comfortable with imperfections and humans. It is still one of the best satisfying feeling to share happinness with friends, families as well as complete strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dokomaps</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/dokomaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/dokomaps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Aimable D. is a close friend since our engineering school days. Like me, he spent time in the corporate world. But he has also done multiple ventures, from eCommerce to corporate to consumer ventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he is focused on &lt;a href=&#34;http://dokomaps.com&#34;&gt;dokomaps&lt;/a&gt;, along with Jules, who worked previously with him on other &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobayilo.com&#34;&gt;ventures&lt;/a&gt;. I am reviewing today Dokomaps to provide feedback, to showcase a good product, but also in the hope that Aimable reviews one of my current ventures, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://outcomereference.com&#34;&gt;OutcomeReference&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pitch&#34;&gt;The Pitch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take the time to visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dokomaps.com&#34;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;. It describes well what you get. Signing up is straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I get from it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dokomaps lets you favorite places, local or international, in personal lists. The list can be for personal use, but they are designed to be shared to the widest audience. Think &amp;ldquo;TOP 10 BEER PLACES&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Top vacations places&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose is simple and will resonate in most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve created two lists. The first is &lt;a href=&#34;https://dokomaps.com/map/176/montreal-for-kids&#34;&gt;Montreal for kids&lt;/a&gt;, divided in the outdoor and indoor categories. The second is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dokomaps.com/map/29/montreal-tech-map&#34;&gt;Montreal tech map&lt;/a&gt;. Creating those two lists were quick. I was able to add any place I could think of. The application finds the geographical coordinates, pictures and then zooms the map on the places. You can also re-order places, so I assume the first ranked place is the best of the category. Is this great or what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-value&#34;&gt;The Value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate value is sharing those lists and getting feedback from friends/family about places I&amp;rsquo;ve missed. I can&amp;rsquo;t think of any other app that provides this now. Or a Google Maps option somewhere?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wishlist&#34;&gt;Wishlist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I thought visitors needed to have an account to view lists you&amp;rsquo;ve just made, making sharing difficult. However, it turned out there are two different URLs, one for you as owner of the list, and another one for sharing. As a user, there was no reason for me to think that there would be a different URL for sharing. This could have been solved by making the sharing URL much more visible, or alternatively, change the structure of the website so there&amp;rsquo;s only 1 URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might appear like a small thing, but I believe this illustrate what dokomaps can improve upon generally. While the user experience is generally good and the product is usable, there are multiple areas that can be perfected, kaizen-style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also thought people who&amp;rsquo;ve signed up should have an option to comment or add their feedback on the list. Otherwise the &amp;ldquo;conversation&amp;rdquo; will migrate outside Dokomaps, such as Facebook or Twitter, which is too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wish there was an option to mark a place as done. For example, if I plan to visit X places, I can use dokomaps and check every place as soon as I&amp;rsquo;m done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final point, I like this venture. It&amp;rsquo;s always refreshing to see a new take that&amp;rsquo;s not done by Google or Facebook, and knowing your data won&amp;rsquo;t be analyzed, ingested and then sold back to you. If Google was doing this, they would know even more about you than you did, and we don&amp;rsquo;t want that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48 Hours Climate Change hackathon</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/hackathon-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 15:30:20 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/hackathon-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am participating this weekend in the AI Climate Change &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/443903349789312/&#34;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;, and I will jot down here my notes and progress. Here is the event pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Join us along with the other talented and diverse participants, supported by leading mentors in their fields who will come together to collaborate to attempt to address climate change and its impacts on communities and ecosystems. We hope to begin to achieve real positive impact in 48 hours using AI. We are also announcing 4 AI challenges: Plant Village Challenge, Extreme Weather Prediction, Climate-Related Risk Assessment, and Predict the Weather in Montréal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a recipe to attract ecologists, students, and dreamers alike. It tells very little about technologies, specific goals and metrics, or  datasets, which are key in AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neverthless, it should be a good opportunity to implement an idea I had recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I used the iOS app &lt;a href=&#34;https://gyrosco.pe&#34;&gt;Gyroscope&lt;/a&gt;, which excels in giving a picture of your daily health. The app has good integration with data providers like Garmin or Apple Health. It was also good at recognizing activities such as walking, biking or taking public transit. At the end of the day, an elegant screen shows total energy expenditure, heart rates, sleep patterns and other core metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://brainhub.eu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/gyroscope-famous-react-native-app.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Health tracking with gyroscope&#34; title=&#34;Health tracking with gyroscope&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitness apps are good into telling you if your work-out was good, but Gyroscope was great into showing if you were getting healthier, overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this ability to track daily actions and giving you a 10,000 feet global view that I want to render, in the case of climate change. Imaging taking an Uber, then getting your Starbucks, having a hamburger at lunch later, then finally biking home. The app will then sum up in a screen what are the positive/negative impact of these actions. You can then share this on social media or just bask in what you&amp;rsquo;ve done that day :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can even imagine, that given enough users and patterns, you could be recommended specific products or actions that improves your &amp;ldquo;climate change balance&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if it sounds like I am a green die-hard activist &amp;ndash; I am not at all. This is just 48 hours of my time trying to build an app that can give key information to people in their life, so they can decide what&amp;rsquo;s best for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a bit of background:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did &lt;a href=&#34;http://outcomereference.com&#34;&gt;outcomereference&lt;/a&gt;, which is able to correlate a food to diseases, and vice-versa. This project is still a work in progress, as it needs more precise statistical modeling, a course that was in my bottom priorities in engineering. But above all, it works and you can trust the results in any page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DIY-Robocars-Montreal-Meetup-Autonomous-cars-race/&#34;&gt;built a couple of self-driving&lt;/a&gt; RC vehicles, based on the donkeycar open source project. So I can do supervised learning, reinforcement learning, computer vision and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also did a lot of AI modeling to know that you have to be either lucky or have an army of supervisers to get an accurate AI model. In 98% of cases, reverting to regressions, mathematical modeling, or brute-forcing with a database works better than an &amp;ldquo;AI model&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did a dozen of web apps, back-end, API or full-stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can do design and UI but it will generally be poor. I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for slick designs so will need help on this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, I foresee a few problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the datasets? and if there aren&amp;rsquo;t any supplied, where do we get them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you actually use an accurate AI model?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the metrics for positive/negative climate change actions? I can think of CO2, but it can be also CH4, or harmful substances (pesticides) and plastics generated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you present something that&amp;rsquo;s simple and elegant for everyone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there even time to train a model and get an accurate model?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are data, back-end, design challenges and I hope to write down here the challenges, analysis, the range of solutions and the course taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued. If you want to contact, I&amp;rsquo;m on twitter @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/heri&#34;&gt;heri&lt;/a&gt; or heri [at] studiozenkai.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday-13-sep-6pm&#34;&gt;Friday 13 Sep - 6pm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoshua Bengio outlines how A.I. can be used, specifically optimizing operations of heavy industry or governments. I think he refers to work done at Element.AI, a commercial entity which works with big businesses. There is no mention of invididual or consumer applications. He also mentions climate and weather modeling, although I am not sure how this can be done in 48 hours. The other presenter, Sasha Luccioni, discusses the actual climate costs of Machine Learning work, and various applications with G.A.N. (??)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a random guy who talks about hugging trees and children and taking a sabbatical leave :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also the first time I go to the MILA / Element.AI building and it reminds me of Facebook/Google/Apple campuses. The building has a surprisingly massive footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my side, I am &lt;em&gt;searching public datasets&lt;/em&gt; that could be used, freely or with a license. &lt;a href=&#34;https://coolclimate.org/calculator&#34;&gt;CoolClimate&lt;/a&gt; has a calculator that uses CO2 for climate change costs with categories in travel, home, food and shopping. It would be possible to deduce activity costs with this calculator, and get sparse data that could be used as a foundation for the app. Another &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.footprintcalculator.org&#34;&gt;calculator&lt;/a&gt; has a better design for everyday users, however it would be hard to &amp;ldquo;reverse engineer&amp;rdquo; this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/Documents/in/Ecological_Footprint&#34;&gt;various papers&lt;/a&gt; in ecological footprints but with my experience with outcomereference, I know these would take forever to read, assimilate and use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also reading an extensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdp.net/en/investor/ghg-emissions-dataset&#34;&gt;study modeling GHG production&lt;/a&gt; and their statistical framework. I think there are some very good lessons here for consumer/invidual applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found a few datasets such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenAMEE/datasets&#34;&gt;OpenAMEE&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mzkarim/Exploring--CO2-Emission-Data-&#34;&gt;CO2 Emissions data&lt;/a&gt; . The first one by OpenAMEE and various forks is especially interesting. I will have to look into the scientific validation of the dataset tomorrow but it is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point however, it is clear there is no extensive public database of ecological footprint of your daily actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other part of the challenge was &lt;em&gt;finding metrics&lt;/em&gt; to qualify daily actions. Interestingly, the CoolClimate calculator seems to correlate all activities with CO2 production. Isn&amp;rsquo;t using CO2 simplistic? Or is it really a standard? I hope I meet a climate change specialist to confirm or deny this tomorrow. Personally, I see &amp;ldquo;climate change&amp;rdquo; as one of the many modern issues that needs to be tackled. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that pesticides, radioactivity or microplastics contribute to climate change for instance, but I see them as important plagues that need action. I might go againt the grain, but I would even rather see climate change rather than having our lands filled with microplastics and chemicals everywhere. Or maybe, CO2, CH4, harmful chemicals can be different components and responses, much alike calories, sleep patterns and mindset are presented in different screens in Gyroscope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the social side, I&amp;rsquo;ve received a lot of positive responses from good folks like Nicole Fu, on the other side of the ocean. She&amp;rsquo;s working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://thecrowd.charity&#34;&gt;The Crowd&lt;/a&gt; app, which compels you to pledge positive climate change. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to look into this tomorrow am. I&amp;rsquo;ve got also good support on Twitter and Facebook. This is great and a sign that we are going in a good direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 7:30pm however and family duty calls. I&amp;rsquo;m wrapping this up and will be here tomorrow 9AM sharp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday-13-sep-late-night-brainstorming&#34;&gt;Friday 13 Sep - Late Night Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have given some thoughts on the footprintcalculator.org design, linked above. They do not tell you figures but rather tell you how many Earths would be needed to support your activities. I like this idea, as this is easy to explain to people, even outside climate change communities, and can also be illustrated elegantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drive an SUV, eat red meat daily, spend thousands on plastic stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t need =&amp;gt; 4.5 Earths&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk/Bike, produce your own veggies, work remotely =&amp;gt; 0.3 Earths&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenAMEE dataset mentioned earlier is also interesting, as it would be straightforward to map into a hierarchical database, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;root activity
__ Transport activity 1.2 Earths
      __ walking 0.02 Earths (or CO2 metric)
      __ biking 0.25 Earths
      __ public transport (subway, electric) 0.85 Earths
      __ public transport (bus, gas) 1.1 Earths
      __ electric car 1.6 Earths
      __ ICE car 2.3 Earths
      __ SUV 3.5 Earths
      __ flying Boeing Dreamliner 7.5 Earths&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could sort siblings at the same level to get the min and max ecological footprint, the median, and also showcase alternative(s). For example, if you take the subway, the app could tell you that walking would have a lower ecological footprint but it would be definitively better than taking a truck for the same trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell me yet how machine learning could be used. I could use Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://storage.googleapis.com/openimages/web/index.html&#34;&gt;Open Images V5&lt;/a&gt; to categorize pictures of activities uploaded. Or maybe do some NLP. This is hard right now to answer because datasets and outputs are not clear. It would be good if a machine learning researcher could look into this tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday-14-sep-design-phase&#34;&gt;Saturday 14 Sep - Design phase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a tentative mockup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/hackathon-mockup.png&#34; alt=&#34;mockup&#34; title=&#34;[hackathon mockup]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could add a picture of their flight. He can add flight duration, and then carbon intensity estimation is shown. This is added as one of his activity. At the end of the day, on the right side, a graph made up of his activities represents his &amp;ldquo;carbon map&amp;rdquo;. This is the key take-away from the app - knowing first what are the impact of each of your activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the user does not enter any input, it is assumed his choices is similar to the baseline, i.e. other people in his city for transport, food, shopping and activities (work, entertainment etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if it could connect to Alexa Smart Home, and deduce your energy consumption, cooking and other activities. Or it could tap into Garmin and many other popular data providers to provide better estimations. Machine Learning could be used further on top to improve carbon footprint estimations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think so far? Head over to Twitter or email me. I&amp;rsquo;d love to discuss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday-14-sep-discussions-and-first-code-lines&#34;&gt;Saturday 14 Sep - Discussions and first code lines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to many people both online and offline, and the general consensus is that this project needs design, from how to ask for user inputs, to how to show information that does not demotivcate users. For example, somebody who is trying to make change in their life might feel discouraged by seeing the amounts of CO2 he generated recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmrowco/tmrowapp-contrib&#34;&gt;tmrow&lt;/a&gt; has been working on this issue for the past 3 years with a solid danish/french team. They have a mobile app and a community base. You can contribute calculations and data to the repository linked earlier. The application is not publicly available so it does limit the usefulness of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry from &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecrowd.charity&#34;&gt;the Crowd Charity&lt;/a&gt; responded a lot of questions regarding datasets and also climate change practices. I feel privileged getting this information and hope to bring back with good work to the community in exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s now less than 24 hours from Demo time in Montreal. Due to this time constraint, I have decided to build an API-based service where third-parties like The Crowd or other can query the carbon cost of various activities. So far, transport  category is covered, with data coming from OpenAMEE and calculations methods based on OpenAMEE sources. If there is no data for a category, the algorithm will look into children categories and get the median cost. All that&amp;rsquo;s left for the user is inputting the number of km for the transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/hackathon-transport.png&#34; alt=&#34;transport&#34; title=&#34;[hackathon mockup]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not foresee having a front-end tomorrow as I will have to work on the other categories such as food, personal, home and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sun-15-sep-final-and-wrap-up&#34;&gt;Sun 15 Sep - Final and Wrap-up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like in most hackathons, there was a severe lack of time towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coded mechanically and did some major copy/pasting for data, as well as bulk csv import 🧟&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application allows you to add your activity, one after the other. It will take the CO2 produced and apply a multiplier. It also gets CH4 production and other greenhouse gas, plus also required energy. There are &amp;ldquo;stochiometry ratios&amp;rdquo; to get the equivalent CO2 for any CH4 produced, as well as public data on CO2 produced per kwH depending on your current location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://studiozenkai.com/images/hackathon-final.png&#34; alt=&#34;final&#34; title=&#34;[hackathon final]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the app sets the location to Canada. Here is a breakdown for these few examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cycling does not produce greenhouse gases. This is good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the mini-bus activity was for 3 hours at 80kmh. The app calculates the distance and then divide by the number of participants to get 3.617 kg CO2. This is not bad as most people will produce more by driving their car in Canada for 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are various activities like washing machine and watching TV. We convert the energy required to CO2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the biggest culprit here is Dairy Cattle. Effectively, raising dairy cattle completely annihilates any climate change efforts. Dairy cattle produce a huge amount of CH4 and CH4 has a high CO2 ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineering-wise, I did not do unfortunately any unit or functional testing. I hate myself but it was about having something up in 30mn vs having something well-engineered. Fortunately, all the calculations and mathematical modeling made sense. I cross-referenced with a few other public calculators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many other teams presented a working mobile app. I found it amazing that they would be able to work and get an accurate model, as well as build an Android or an iOS app. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have time to do some css. I remember a few years ago teams would struggle even to get a single web app working. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested (holla or tweet at @heri), I can put this online as a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-16-sep-future&#34;&gt;Monday 16 Sep - Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next? To make this usable, the service needs to be tied to various data providers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MyFitnessPal logs your food. If I can connect to their API, I can associate each ingredient to their carbon footprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would need to find a trusted service that logs your car trips and your flights, plus the type of car driven. This needs research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are popular fitness trackers such as Fitbit, Garmin or Google Fit that logs your bike and walking trips. This can be integrated and show your carbon intensity (or lack thereof)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It looks like due to privacy reasons, there is no public API for Smart Homes. I could be wrong, but there is no way for example to list what are your smart appliances and when they run with Alexa Home, or the Google/Apple equivalent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using these data providers would be a much more seamless experience for potential users, since they get immediate results, and potentially immediate recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love also to sit down with a climate change scientist to validate calculations. Plus good design people and marketing. Damn, that sounds like a team &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll share this on social networks and see where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchlab.ai&#34;&gt;MTLNewTech&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchlab.ai&#34;&gt;AI Launch Lab&lt;/a&gt; who have organized the hackathon. I know from first hand how much dedication it takes to create such an event spanning several days. The food was delicious, coffee was plenty and there was a good diversity of attendees. A special holla to Ilias Benjeloun who gave his 120% and came the whole 3 days, even though he got a cold towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an autonomous RC car</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/autonomous-rc-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/autonomous-rc-car/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is a hands-on article that encourages you to experiment and see what works on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shameless Promotion&lt;/em&gt;: If you are in Montréal, I (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/heri&#34;&gt;@heri&lt;/a&gt;) do a meetup where people interested in computer vision, AI, robotics work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DIY-Robocars-Montreal-Meetup-Autonomous-cars-race&#34;&gt;autonomous cars&lt;/a&gt;. Please drop by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-a-rc-car&#34;&gt;Why a RC car?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like developing an application, my recommendation is to build first a &lt;em&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/em&gt; (MVP). Then iterate it quickly from there towards a version that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An autonomous car is at the bare minimum able to follow a course, without any input from a human driver. That is an engineering challenge, both on the hardware and software side. The car manufacturer needs to install a wide array of sophisticated sensors, ranging from cameras, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lidar&#34;&gt;LIDAR&lt;/a&gt;, GPS to engine sensors. It also requires actuators so a computer can drive the engine, gears and steering. The software has to ingest a huge flow of data, decide on the best route based on missing or conflicting data, and make sure not to harm anything in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These constraints means making a autonomous car is costly and prohibitive for most. If you want to build a life-sized self-driving car, you need to join a team at Waymo, Baidu, Yandex or another billion dollar company like Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;hack&lt;/em&gt; is to work on an RC car, instead of a life-size car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RC cars are plenty available. The smartphone and drones boom means there are plenty of cheap and diverse sensors and parts usable for your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RC cars are also light, which means an accident will not create body injury. If a part breaks, you can replace it easily and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, RC cars can have simpler autonomous software. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a mission planner. Object tracking is not necessary. The MVP can just have track recognition. This is good news for those who want to study computer vision or neural networks, without being a specialist in hardware, mapping, motion planning or in Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this means development costs and times are cut down. Instead of months and years, you could have your first autonomous in a few weeks time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anatomy-of-an-autonomous-rc-car&#34;&gt;Anatomy of an autonomous RC car&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An autonomous RC car mirrors a life-size car, with simpler parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A main motor with a transmission,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A battery,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one ESC or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_speed_control&#34;&gt;Electronic Speed Controller&lt;/a&gt;. The ESC will run the motor,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.servocity.com/what-is-a-servo&#34;&gt;servo&lt;/a&gt;, for steering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensor. At the bare minimum, you will need one wide-angle camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer or equivalent to record, run inference based on data from sensor and send outputs to the servo and ESC. A Raspberry Pi is good for the first version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A RC transmitter/Receiver. Instead, you will use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General-purpose_input/output&#34;&gt;GPIO pins&lt;/a&gt; of a Raspberry pi to send signals to the ESC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A RC body. Electronics should be easily accessible and replaceable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A gearbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn signals (blinkers), brakes or headlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a GPU card or TPUs, at least not in the beginning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the software side, a RC car has a main python program that decides what to do next based on image recorded. Here, you can use either machine learning (Deep Learning/CNN/Tensorflow/&lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/&#34;&gt;Keras&lt;/a&gt;) or traditional computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For computer vision, the best way to start is with &lt;a href=&#34;http://openmv.io&#34;&gt;OpenMV.io&lt;/a&gt;. The camera has a board that will do the calculations such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://openmv.io/collections/cams/products/openmv-cam-m7&#34;&gt;line detection&lt;/a&gt;, contrast/exposure changes. In the case of an autonomous car using CV such as Teslas, it will use a basic technique called &amp;ldquo;blob tracking&amp;rdquo; that shows a center point, which tells the car how to steer to stay on the line. See the code and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://diyrobocars.com/2018/11/23/updated-minimal-viable-racer-to-use-latest-openmv-linear-regression-code/&#34;&gt;DIY Robocar post here&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s less sophisticated and less &lt;em&gt;trendy&lt;/em&gt; than machine learning, but produces good results as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For machine learning, the application will have at its core a convolutional neural network taught with supervised learning. This means the neural network is trained on an external computer using image frames from the RC camera and then run the inference model on the edge computer to generate the corresponding outputs to the servo and the motor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very similar to computational photography on Huawei or Google phones. Engineers took a variety of images from the camera, annotated parts of the image that should be blurry (aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bokeh&#34;&gt;bokeh&lt;/a&gt; ). Each user can then produce portraits with bokeh on their phone, based on the model trained in the previous step. But instead of motor signals, it produces bokeh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is fortunately the amazing &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.donkeycar.com&#34;&gt;Donkeycar&lt;/a&gt; project that has ready-to-use software and hardware instructions. There are links to find the appropriate parts, and if you are stuck, there is also an active community on Slack. There are also good projects like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RyanZotti/Self-Driving-Car&#34;&gt;RyanZotti&lt;/a&gt; which works well for smaller RC cars and Lego, the Udacity stack or Apollo. However, Donkeycar is the most usable and beginner-friendly in my opinion. You don&amp;rsquo;t need soldiering and you don&amp;rsquo;t need a lot of extra electronics to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you combine the hardware and software and want to launch your first RC autonomous car, the process is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put together a track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connect through SSH to the Raspberry Pi, and then access driving controls on the web, or with a controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try to drive a few laps, like what a real good driver would do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once you are sure of your driving skills, begin recording laps. All image frames and inputs (throttle, steering angle) will be recorded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transfer training data to the main computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;training is done typically on a beefy computer with a recent Nvidia card, or otherwise on a cloud server with a GPU (Google Compute or Amazon). The loss value represents the difference between what the neural network computes and what would be an ideal output. You will want to minimize this, without overfitting the model. Once you&amp;rsquo;re happy with a loss value, you can validate it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the trained model with your RC car, and race it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t done neural networks, this is a great way to understand how it works, and perhaps have your first AI application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that is the Minimum Viable Product. Other developments could be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use instead an Nvidia Jetson board. This is much more powerful, and better suited for machine learning. Models can be trained and run directly on the board, without requiring an external computer with GPU. You can add easily multiple cameras, speed sensors, LIDAR, GPS without any issues, and run at the same time a mission planner. However it consumes significantly more power compared to a Raspberry Pi, costs at least x5 more, and takes so much space that you will have to upgrade to a &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; RC car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a good driver of RC cars, or become a very good driver. Because after all, A.I. only learns from your inputs. This is what most people forget. Everyone wants to buy more expensive cameras, or just write more code. Often, models are fed garbage. It can be only as good as you are. This is why big corporations like Waymo require driver trainers with a &lt;em&gt;spotless&lt;/em&gt; driving history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve electronic parts so the RC car becomes more precise and more responsive. Often, RC cars have too much torque, imprecise steering, and also have a delay compared to life-size cars,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_steering&#34;&gt;differential steering&lt;/a&gt;. It can be a RC tracked vehicle, or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mars_rover&#34;&gt;Mars Rover&lt;/a&gt;-style robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the machine learning model. You can track &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arxiv_cscv&#34;&gt;arXiv CV&lt;/a&gt;, and check out recent self-driving or computer vision papers. You can then try to implement the algorithm presented, if there is minimal code. You can work on reinforcement learning, data augmentation, use different kernel size, lens correction, sensor fusion etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add actuators. For example, add a loader, or snowplow system. For example, this guy developed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackster.io/abdullahsadiq/autonomous-delivery-system-4c2048&#34;&gt;a package delivery system&lt;/a&gt; based on the donkeycar! Isn&amp;rsquo;t that amazing? Now you can have your $100m VC funded startup with open source electronics :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add sensors for better depths perception, for example to prevent collisions. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dfrobot.com/product-1125.html&#34;&gt;LIDARs for $99&lt;/a&gt;. Or add an IMU (angle/orientation sensor), add a GPS, beacon system etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add obstacles, small pedestrians models, traffic lights, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the knowledge and extend it to autonomous boats, rockets, planes. There are competitions for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.herox.com/alphapilot&#34;&gt;autonomous flight drones&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate more complex autonomous software such as Autoware or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ApolloAuto/apollo&#34;&gt;Apollo&lt;/a&gt; and make it run a complex command. Such as go pickup package at point A, go to point B, wait for a signal, then park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://roboticsmasters.co/fullsizecars/&#34;&gt;autonomous car kits&lt;/a&gt; for real cars. Another kit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/commaai/openpilot&#34;&gt;running openpilot&lt;/a&gt; is provided by comma.ai for recent Toyota/Honda cars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly suggest taking a lean approach. Do step by step improvements, save every model you&amp;rsquo;ve validated. It&amp;rsquo;s better to have regular small improvements than try to go big and then fail big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are around, we&amp;rsquo;d love to have you at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DIY-Robocars-Montreal-Meetup-Autonomous-cars-race/events/259007280/&#34;&gt;our next meetup this wednesday Feb 27&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://diyrobocars.com/local-meetup-groups/&#34;&gt;check other meetups near you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @joshnuss @166inter @MassimoFarina for their valuable feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I want for Christmas is a small phone</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/small-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/small-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got an iPhone 6S Plus a few years ago. I was impressed by the screen, the biggest I’ve had. Look! I can use it as a tablet. Watch videos everywhere, or showcase my latest work at a tech meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dreams shattered in many pieces. I was biking happily, the phone was sticking out of my pocket and crashed to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bike a lot, hike, run around hilly tracks and never cracked a screen before the iPhone 6S Plus. Previous phones could fit in a normal pocket. In an instant, I realized why large screen phones did not work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the iPhone 6S Plus, electronics manufacturers seems to compete against each other in size. More screen real estate, more cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not want big screens anymore. Even today, I do not know how to hold it when I run or exercise. Do you keep it on your hand? Or buy a special attachment and put it on your shoulder? I run for peace of mind, and having a big dangling phone seemed to defeat the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get in a similar akward situation when I meet friends for lunch. When phones are big, you do not want to keep it in a pocket. It finishes on the table. This separates us. The phone becomes a talking point and becomes part of your identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use my phone for two factor authentication. This means the phone is the key for assets worth $10k - or $5k depending on cryptocurrency prices… I don’t want to put such a key asset on a table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools I like best are forgettable when I do not use them, are user friendly, and do not require special treatment. And they definitively do not define my behaviour. This is not the case of phones with 6 inches display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for this Christmas, I will go against the grain to want less, not more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 inch would be a good size to start with. I could forget in my pants pocket. I could put it in my runner shorts and go run for a couple of hours, without noticing the weight. 6 inches would not fit in those short shorts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it waterproof, dust-proof and a minimum shock-proof so I don’t have a heart attack when a baby plays with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fingerprint sensor. Please, no face recognition. Showing my face doesn’t mean I want to unlock it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headphone jack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large camera (&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.3 to 1”) with computational photography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, an expandable phone, such as being able to connect it to a raspberry pi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I don’t want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a phone made of glass or other luxury material. In the real world, a phone falls, is a toy for kids, is covered by sweat when you run, and bumped against coins and metal keys. And it not an object I am willing to replace by the latest trendy gizmo every 18 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a notch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a phone that costs $1000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an assistant that spies your browsing history, your location or your audio to serve ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this somehow describes an iPhone 5S with an upgraded camera, with the durability of a Nokia 3310. I would get one. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you? Let’s hope a product manager hears this somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking again at Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 12:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The natural cycle of companies is to innovate. The flame dies down, then it fights again to innovate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is one of those. Win 3.1 was revolutionary, and so was Win 95. With Win 3.1, you could point and click to start programs. With Windows 95, you could install games with a nice GUI instead of typing arduous commands in MS-DOS. No more failures at the video setup or having to find a driver file for your sound card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, Microsoft went greedy. Instead of optimizing for good products, the mega corporation optimized for dollars. It sued any organization threatening its dominant position. Innovation was adding recycled buttons and rows in Microsoft Office. This was good for shareholders but made everyone’s life worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time I switched to an Apple iBook. The white plastic made it look like a toy, but it “just worked”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; recently. To my surprise, it is a very well built piece of software. I remember Microsoft Visual Studio in engineering school. You needed to be “corporate” to go past the licensing pages, then feel out of place if you didn’t read 500 pages of C#. My initial computer science dreams died there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report VS Code is lightweight and lets you work right away. I have been using it for more than 18 months and have yet to find an issue. It just works. Previous Microsoft products could do everything and nothing. VS Code took courageous design choices so it performs well in the few things it&amp;rsquo;s designed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, I have 3 to 5 workspaces open at the same time. A workspace has at least two folders, each folder representing an application. That is tens of thousands of javascript, ruby, python, shell, css/html files. I can search and replace a pattern in a 440MB log file, and it will not crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom.io is a similar code editor from  Github. It also uses Electron. But where VS Code shines, Atom.io chokes up on large javascript files (&amp;gt;1Mb). I am not sure if Atom.io tries to execute the javascript or if it has a weak rendering engine. It is “OK” for editing text files or quick coding, but unproductive for a large project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sublime Text is a nice native code editor. But I prefer VS Code&amp;rsquo;s built-in Github integration, workspaces, and extensions. TextMate, another code editor I used for years, also “just works”, but is dated. Now, I only use VS Code and vim for programming, on a Macbook Pro or a Windows or Linux laptop. It even works on Raspbian!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VS Code is not an exception. I like the Microsoft Surface hardware line-up. The Surface Book could be a nice Macbook Pro replacement, if Windows had a good Terminal. I haven’t had the chance to try Azure, but I’ve been told it holds up compared to AWS or DigitalOcean, my preferred hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, somebody at Microsoft got people working together and started caring about making their users’ life easier. In other words, they started optimizing for good products, instead of optimizing for dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few good things I would love to see to commit fully to Microsoft:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rendering fonts and subpixels is sketchy compared to Apple, no matter the screen resolution. Is it possible to get one of your hardware designer to work on this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would love if Microsoft (or Apple) made fingerprint profiles. If I use my fingerprint, allow access to all apps and data. If it’s a kid’s fingerprint, disable the App Store, and allow Youtube for a limited time. If it’s not a recognized fingerprint, show a clean desktop, with the rest of the data encrypted. I see computing devices as tools. I can share a tool or a car with a family member, why can’t you do the same with computing devices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Linux Terminal. I would like to use shell scripts, docker in Windows, use ssh and any other tool I use in a Linux/Ubuntu machine. Please?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget about telemetry and offer complete privacy by default. We do not want devices that phones home or with back doors. If you treat us as pirates or irresponsible kids, we will become pirates and irresponsible kids. Please trust your users and we will trust you too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know you are working on a new browser. For the love of common sense, find a way to solve the GDPR, cookie popups, adtech and privacy abuses. Why can’t we have a browser setting “I accept/I do not accept cookies for all sites”? So it gets rids of all annoying popups. Why don’t we have the browser handle privacy? Browsers should be able to give websites a key to private data information, after a fingerprint confirmation. Once you are finished with a site, you could ask the browser to terminate access to the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t annoy me with updates and questions. MacOS started asking constantly if it can update software and reboot. This interrupts my workflow and makes me think it is broken. If there is a critical update, and the core software needs to be updated, just do it, without interruption. If it is not a critical update, please give us an option “I will update my software manually” so we do not have to agree to a software update every week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Performance checklist</title>
      <link>https://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-performance-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-performance-checklist/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I shipped many applications, using a variety of frameworks, through &lt;a href=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/challenge/&#34;&gt;my current 1 year challenge&lt;/a&gt; or startups. Ruby issues include low performance, such as servers needing more RAM, not able to sustain large traffic, or slow rendering. Since this is a recurring issue, here is a checklist to help developers get their Ruby app faster:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-complexity&#34;&gt;Code complexity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and ease of use allows beginners and experienced developers alike to ship features in record time. Good for business, otherwise bad for code quality. For instance, many :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create too many instance variables and statements. This means more allocations and more database calls. Often the variables are not even used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add too many loops. This exponentially decreases performance. Do you need yet another &lt;code&gt;each&lt;/code&gt; or collection?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use too many gems. There are many nice gems to make you life easier. Few however think if they need yet another gem. Don&amp;rsquo;t bloat your app!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less complex code is more readable and brings in most cases more performance. I like to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/whitesmith/rubycritic&#34;&gt;rubycritic&lt;/a&gt; to bring more sanity. Another alternative is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbatsov/rubocop&#34;&gt;rubocop&lt;/a&gt;. There are also third-party services like skylight to show you object allocation. Pick your tool, and focus efforts on the most complex methods. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to write terse one-liners. However there is a always a happy middle ground that will satisfy developers and product owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;database-calls&#34;&gt;Database calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ActiveRecord or Sequel makes life easier for Ruby developers. Perhaps too easy. If left unchecked, you find yourself doing hundreds of queries for a single page. Get the blog post, get the post comments, then get the comment users, and then their pictures. And why not the list of people who liked, or favorited the post. And&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and easy solution is stop doing N+1 queries. Use a gem like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flyerhzm/bullet&#34;&gt;bullet&lt;/a&gt; or a service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoutapp.com/&#34;&gt;scoutapp&lt;/a&gt; to hunt N+1 queries. These allow you to set alert on Slack, or any similar messenging service, in case of a N+1 query. See an alert as a failure that needs to be solved before the end of the day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another (and less easy) path is start learning and loving Postgres (or MySQL, if that&amp;rsquo;s your database of choice). This will take time, but you will then be able to start using advanced joins, custom types such as ranges, arrays, json, spatial types, or good full-text searches. Please investigate to make best use of existing resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops-for-ruby&#34;&gt;DevOps for Ruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you have a dedicated DevOps or an infrastructure engineer in your team, I advise generally Ruby developers to learn how to deploy, manage and scale servers. This will allow you to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn load balancing or reverse proxy cache. See into Nginx scripting, through Lua or Ruby, to dramatically increase performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn how to sustain good performance, even with limited hardware or service disruptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn the pros and cons of passenger vs puma vs unicorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn how to commit and deploy without service uninterruption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-caching&#34;&gt;The art of caching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caching can be done at multiple levels: front server, database, app, assets etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite is ETag. Everyone wants to use Redis but smart use of etags lets you render pages in 40ms or less. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to beat. In the example of the blog post, the &lt;code&gt;updated_at&lt;/code&gt; column lets us bypass rendering or data loading. ETag also works for API calls so do not be shy in using ETag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another low-hanging fruit is caching. Most often, rendering a collection with a partial takes most of the time for a page render. Using &lt;code&gt;cached: true&lt;/code&gt; increases performance. Once you have a store for caching, you can also store results of complex queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, Redis will be your best friend. It&amp;rsquo;s stable as a rock, will ingest anything you throw at it, is extensible and super-fast. With a bit of work, you can serve requests from 100kreq/s to 1mreq/s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-impression-of-speed&#34;&gt;The impression of speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say performance is in the eye of beholder. A static page means slow performance for users. However doing the following will make them think otherwise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using frameworks like React allows them to load instantly pages. The visitor can be &amp;ldquo;distracted&amp;rdquo; by a loading animation and/or various parts of the page moving. You can also let them enter data on a form while data loads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On select browsers such as Chrome or Firefox, service workers let users continue using the page, even if the server is slow or even unreachable. Performance is then only related to the performance of the front-end app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplement data can be loaded later. In the example of the article, we get the page title and content text in one query. However, comments can be loaded only when the user scrolls down to the relevant section. In a similar way, you can defer content requiring heavy calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other UI patterns to give the impression of speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;offloading&#34;&gt;Offloading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business goals might require a maximum render time. In this case, you can offload complex processing to a job server, most often Sidekiq/Redis. You can for example use this job server&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To send emails and notify users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To work on the database, such as calculations, data processing, data import and export&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To process media, such as encoding videos, resizing images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and generally any job that might slow down your main app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A drawback is that a job might fail. Or data might have changed between the job creation and job processing. Sidekiq is also not as reliable as Redis. Overall, data offloading might confuse users by presenting obsolete data - leading them to reload pages, spam customer service, or just quit. Make sure to test!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sub-optimization&#34;&gt;Sub-optimization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have done all the above, with lean methods, smart use of caching, and a good UI, I might still be unsatisfied with Ruby performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to optimize key parts of your application by using C or Rust code. For example, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamSaffron/fast_blank&#34;&gt;fast_blank&lt;/a&gt; gem makes blank? statements 20x faster. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ohler55/oj&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;oj&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a JSON parser written in C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/danielpclark/faster_path&#34;&gt;faster_path&lt;/a&gt;, written in Rust, can optimize file loading. There is a also the newer &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tildeio/helix&#34;&gt;Helix&lt;/a&gt; gem, that I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested yet, to easily add Rust to your Rails application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to test extensively (esp. unit tests)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-really-need-rails&#34;&gt;Do you really need Rails?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies dealing with poor Ruby performance use Ruby on Rails. Ruby on Rails is a heavyweight, the hungry yokozuna that will eat any available RAM. Yet in many cases, we don&amp;rsquo;t need all the Active Support methods or everything that Active Record gives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeremyevans/roda&#34;&gt;roda&lt;/a&gt;, a micro Ruby framework, is faster than Phoenix, Play (a scala framework) and can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techempower.com/benchmarks/previews/round14/#section=data-r14&amp;amp;hw=ph&amp;amp;test=query&#34;&gt;as fast as nodejs&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&#34;http://hanamirb.org/&#34;&gt;Hanami&lt;/a&gt; is another framework that will deliver superior performance compared to Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ve used a standalone Roda app or Hanami, in parallel to a Rails app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;json search results for the application. roda outputs a db query to json. These are sent to a React/Angular front-end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embedding content. Bloggers and users looking to embed an object on their site or social media are served by roda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building a simple/minimalistic admin area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also used other frameworks such as Phoenix framework or in rare occasions Lapis (which uses OpenResty/nginx) or ExpressJs. Phoenix lies on top of the Erlang VM and is almost impossible to kill. Scheduling background processing jobs is nice experience compared to Rails - stress-free and more natural. However the language is not as expressive as Ruby and you find yourself writing more lines (!). Like Phoenix, Lapis is another high-performance framework written in Lua, however the community is quite small. You can also check out golang frameworks such as beego. Not bad, however I would use a go framework only on select projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, it is hard to write a definitive performance guide that will work for most applications. A few applications require just a bit of front-end UI work solve all performance issues (i.e. add a spinner gif and everyone&amp;rsquo;s happy). Others require hand-crafted SQL queries. Sometimes, it&amp;rsquo;s just about beefing up server hardware. Use tools like scout-apm, skylight or newrelic. Work on the low-hanging fruits and then move up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for performance ideas, I advise taking one of your legacy apps and try to increase performance by 3x or 10x within a 48H hackathon. This exercise will force you to work on creative solutions and will teach you valuable technics for working applications later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss, feel free to contact me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/heri&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or email heri@studiozenkai.com or comment on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14299690&#34;&gt;HN post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
