<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Studio Zenkai on Studio Zenkai </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://studiozenkai.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 08 May 2017 10:35:26 EDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Performance checklist</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-performance-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/ruby-performance-checklist/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I shipped many applications, using a variety of frameworks, through &lt;a href=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/challenge/&#34;&gt;my current 1 year challenge&lt;/a&gt; or startups. Ruby issues include low performance, such as servers needing more RAM, not able to sustain large traffic, or slow rendering. Since this is a recurring issue, here is a checklist to help developers get their Ruby app faster:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-complexity&#34;&gt;Code complexity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and ease of use allows beginners and experienced developers alike to ship features in record time. Good for business, otherwise bad for code quality. For instance, many :&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why my next laptop won&#39;t be an Apple</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/laptop-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 15:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/laptop-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i-apple-s-craftmanship&#34;&gt;Part I - Apple&amp;rsquo;s Craftmanship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used the original macbook, the 13&amp;rdquo; MacBook Air, the 13&amp;rdquo; Macbook pro, and 15&amp;rdquo; Macbook pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the white plastic of the original macbook. It was better than any other computer I&amp;rsquo;ve used before, worked out of the box, and iMovie amazed me. Drag, drop, and five minutes later, you have a video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://studiozenkai.com/images/macbook_white.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;macbook white&#34; title=&#34;[macbook white]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought this is what computing should be.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why bots are a thing now</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/bots/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Upon hearing about Facebook and Microsoft efforts to deploy bot platforms, a friend reacted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So bots are a thing now? I programmed bots 20 years ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a successful technology entrepreneur and has developed systems on many platforms. I can understand him. There were tutorials in kids&amp;rsquo; magazines on writing a &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; bot on MS-DOS 20 years ago. More impressive were the Artificial Intelligence (A.I.) found in games like Warcraft 3 or Command &amp;amp; Conquer. Friends would spend countless nights trying to beat the A.I. For everyone else, it would be the Clipper found in Microsoft Word. It had personality and would show tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time, bots and A.I. were rule-based. &amp;ldquo;If player produces infantry, produce infantry-killing robots&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;If user clicks print, show links on how to print&amp;rdquo;. To get user satisfaction, you need to write rules covering all cases, as well as the exceptions. It is a creative and long but easy job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s clipper or video games AI showed their limits. &lt;em&gt;Apart from clear cases, bots could not process subtle situations&lt;/em&gt;. Typing a wrong letter would leave the bot stuck for example. Using a different expression would not work. Creative players would find ways to beat the A.I. in ways unseen by video game designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, bots and A.I. seem to be commercial hype by bored journalists, like 3D movies two years ago. You can reuse old code, add a few words like A.I or &amp;ldquo;intelligent&amp;rdquo; in a press release, and get coverage by gullible bloggers. Fast forward a few months and you get millions from investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example is not far-fetched. The majority of startups on Techcrunch do not have true technology innovation. Yet, there is true disruption. Here is why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bots-in-a-mobile-world&#34;&gt;Bots in a mobile world&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a self-taught programmer</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 12:55:51 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In six months I have shipped many apps, as an entrepreneur or as a freelancer. I have also contributed to open source projects and advised other projects. Yet I’m educated as an electrical engineer, not as a software engineer and consider myself largely self-taught in the area of programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Atwood : Geeks went from being social outsiders, outcasts, and rejects to.. part of the 1% power structure, with all that implies. Hard to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in Québec, there are about 7000 programmer or developer positions that are not filled every month. As a result, small and big companies are fighting to get the attention of programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just in Québec. Go in Toronto, New York city or in California. It seems you can find a highly rewarding job as long as you know how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*R5FJAuwICPzY3ByLnkgpCg.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Barack Obama Code&#34; title=&#34;[Barack Obama Code]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trend has not gotten unnoticed. Smart people from all horizons are now learning and looking to land a job in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is for those people in arts, marketing and many other fields who are now looking for the best way to learn how to code in six months. Since time is limited, it is focused on producing practical code instead of abstract topics such as data structures or compiling. I assume however that it is just the beginning of a journey and you will have time later on to pick on formal learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-learning-environment&#34;&gt;Building a learning environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any laptop or desktop is good to learn. However, it cannot be a phone or a tablet (no programming on iPhones folks!). It doesn’t matter if it’s Mac, PC or Linux as long as you have admin access and you are able to install anything you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;interruptions-kill-productivity&#34;&gt;Interruptions kill productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning programming is in a quiet environment, with little to no interruptions. Set aside at the very minimum two hours per day, ideally a good five hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-taught programming in 2015 is done with a relatively decent Internet connection. It means you can download a 50MB package without interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn-from-the-best&#34;&gt;Learn from the best&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playbook</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 12:22:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/playbook/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Bonjour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nous offrons &lt;em&gt;une expertise technique pour un résultat de qualité&lt;/em&gt; dans le développement de plateformes transactionnelles, de financement, de médias:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Étude et conception fonctionnelle et technique&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Développement de solutions front, middle ou back-office&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Développement d&amp;rsquo;applications iOS ou Android&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conduite de projet sur les technologies Ruby, Javascript, Lua, et plateformes mobiles; utilisation de base de données MySQL, Postgresql, ou redis, mongodb, ElasticSearch, Solr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuda Cores Ranking for Machine learning</title>
      <link>http://studiozenkai.com/post/cuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 10:35:26 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://studiozenkai.com/post/cuda/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA graphic cards can be used to accelerate &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/gpu-accelerated-libraries&#34;&gt;scientific computing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn&#34;&gt;neural networks&lt;/a&gt;, video games and occasionally bitcoin computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video editing and post-production also benefit greatly from NVIDIA cards with Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Mercury Engine or BMD&amp;rsquo;s Davinci resolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of scientific computing, performance is directly proportional to the number of cuda cores. As long as cpu speed is &amp;gt; 2GHz and you have as much RAM as you have GPU RAM, you are all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, this lists current top 10 laptops that have a good price vs cuda cores # ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
